You can add new tools and capabilities to Claude Code
Claude Code에 새로운 도구와 기능을 추가할 수 있습니다.
through the use of MCP servers. These
MCP 서버를 사용해서요. 이
MCP servers either run remotely or locally
MCP 서버는 원격 또는 로컬에서 실행됩니다.
on your machine. A very popular MCP
사용자 기기에서요. 아주 인기 있는 MCP
server named Playwright gives Claude Code the
서버인 Playwright는 Claude Code에
ability to control a browser. Let me show you how to
브라우저를 제어하는 기능을 제공합니다. 어떻게
add it to Claude Code, and then we'll use it to develop
Claude Code에 추가하는지 보여드리겠습니다. 그리고
our app a little bit more. To install the server at
나서 그걸로 앱을 좀 더 개발해 볼 거예요. 서버를 설치하려면
your terminal, not inside of Claude Code, we'll execute
Claude Code 안이 아니라 터미널에서
Claude MCP Add. And then a name
Claude MCP Add를 실행합니다. 그리고 이름은
for this MCP server, I'm going to name it playwright. And
이 MCP 서버의 이름을 playwright라고 붙일게요. 그리고
then after the name, we'll add in a command that will start up
이름 뒤에는 로컬에서 서버를 시작하는
the server locally on your machine. We can then start
명령어를 추가합니다. 그러면
Claude Code and ask it to open a browser and navigate
Claude Code를 시작하고 브라우저를 열어
to our application at localhost 3000.
localhost 3000의 저희 애플리케이션으로 이동하라고
Before the browser opens, you might notice that you are required to give
요청할 수 있습니다. 브라우저가 열리기 전에 해당 도구를
permission for that tool to run. If you get tired
실행하도록 권한을 부여해야 한다는 점을 알 수 있습니다.
of all those permission pop-ups, you can open up the Claude
이 모든 권한 팝업이 귀찮다면 Claude
directory inside their settings.local.json.
디렉토리의 settings.local.json 파일을 열어보세요.
And then inside of the allow array, you can add in a
그리고 allow 배열 안에 MCP 언더스코어 언더스코어
string of MCP underscore underscore,
(언더스코어가 두 개 있다는 점에 유의하세요),
notice there are two underscores there, playwright. This
playwright를 추가할 수 있습니다. 이것은
allows Claude Code to make use of this MCP server and
Claude Code가 이 MCP 서버와
the tools inside of it in any way it wants without requiring
그 안의 도구들을 마음대로 사용할 수 있게 해주고,
you to provide permission every time. If I restart
매번 권한을 부여할 필요가 없습니다. Claude
Claude Code and then ask it to open a browser again,
Code를 다시 시작하고 브라우저를 열어달라고
it will do so without requiring me to give permission. There
다시 요청하면 권한 부여 없이 그렇게 할 것입니다.
are incredible number of ways that you can use the Playwright MCP
Playwright MCP 서버를 사용할 수 있는 방법은
server. Let me show you one that would be really applicable to the
엄청나게 많습니다. 지금 작업 중인
project we are working on right now. Back inside
프로젝트에 정말 유용할 한 가지 방법을 보여드리겠습니다.
my editor, I'm going to find the SRC, Lib, prompts,
편집기 안으로 돌아가서 SRC, Lib, prompts,
generation.tsx file. This is the prompt
generation.tsx 파일을 찾을 것입니다. 이것은
that is used to actually generate the components that you ask
저희 앱에서 요청한 컴포넌트를 실제로 생성하는 데 사용되는 프롬프트입니다.
for inside of our app. So I want to allow
그래서 저는 Claude Code가
Claude Code to make use of the browser, generate
브라우저를 사용하도록 하고, 자체적으로
a component on its own, and then tweak this prompt
컴포넌트를 생성한 다음, 이 프롬프트를
on its own based upon the generated component. And
생성된 컴포넌트를 기반으로 자체적으로 수정하도록
hopefully, we'll end up with some better looking components
하고 싶습니다. 그러면
being generated out of our app. So let me show you how
저희 앱에서 더 보기 좋은 컴포넌트가 생성될 것입니다.
we would do that. Back inside of Claude Code, I'm going to ask
어떻게 하는지 보여드릴게요. Claude Code로 돌아가서
it to navigate to localos3000.
localhost 3000으로 이동하라고 요청할 것입니다.
attempt to generate a component, take a look at the
컴포넌트를 생성하려고 시도하고,
generated source code and evaluate the styling, and
생성된 소스 코드를 살펴보고 스타일을 평가한 다음,
then update our prompt inside that generation.tsx
generation.tsx 파일 안의 프롬프트를 수정할 것입니다.
file, and hopefully we'll end up with some at
그러면 하루가 끝날 때쯤 생성된 컴포넌트의
the end of the day better styling on our generated components.
스타일이 더 좋아지기를 바랍니다.
up the browser. It's going to attempt to generate a component.
브라우저를 열고 컴포넌트를 생성하려고 시도할 것입니다.
it's not quite so happy. You might actually notice
그것이 그렇게 만족스럽지 않은 것 같습니다.
that it complains about a very common style that's used in
이런 종류의 애플리케이션에서 흔히 사용되는
applications like this, a purple to blue kind
스타일, 즉 보라색에서 파란색으로 가는
of gradient. Claude is then going to update
그라디언트에 대해 불평하는 것을 볼 수 있습니다. Claude는
our prompt and then try to generate a new component.
저희 프롬프트를 수정하고 새 컴포넌트를 생성하려고
a much better result than I ever expected. This
이것은 제가 예상했던 것보다 훨씬 더 좋은 결과를
testimonial card actually looks really, really great. Based
주었습니다. 이 추천 카드는 정말 정말 멋져 보입니다.
on these results alone, you can immediately get a sense that
이 결과만 봐도 MCP 서버가
MCP servers really open the door to a lot of interesting
얼마나 많은 흥미로운 사용 사례를 열어주는지
use cases. And I highly recommend you look into some
바로 느낄 수 있습니다. 그리고 Claude가
MCP servers that might aid Claude in developing
사용자분이 개인적으로 작업 중인 어떤 프로젝트든
whatever kind of project you personally are working on.
개발하는 데 도움이 될 만한 MCP 서버를 찾아보시길 강력히 권장합니다.